casalemedia.com 2013-06-15

# Casale Media - Privacy Policy

| Casale Media participates in TRUSTe's Privacy and Trusted Data Collection Programs.  
TRUSTe privacy seals help thousands of businesses promote online safety and trust, and guide consumers to websites that protect their privacy online. |  | 

---|---|---  
  
This privacy policy covers the data collection and use practices of Casale Media's Online Advertising Network (MediaNet) and website, www.casalemedia.com. Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to our users' privacy, we have agreed to disclose our privacy practices and have them reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. If users have questions or concerns regarding this policy, you should first contact us. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). 

TRUSTe will serve as a liaison to resolve users concerns. 

|  |   
  
**Online Advertising Network (MediaNet)  
** The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices of the Casale Media Online Advertising Network (MediaNet). 

Casale Media believes in all Internet users' rights to privacy. All information collected by the Casale Media Online Advertising Network (MediaNet) is not personally identifiable as it relates to consumers. 

**Cookies  
** A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a website's computer and stored on your computer's hard drive. 

The Casale Media Online Advertising Network (MediaNet) uses cookies for the purpose of tracking when an Internet user has seen an advertisement. These cookies do not and cannot provide Casale Media with any personally identifiable information about an Internet user. These cookies serve two purposes: 

  1. They are used to inform the Casale Media Online Advertising Network (MediaNet) whether or not an advertisement has been served to the same computer before, and if so, when the advertisement was served. These cookies are not used by Casale Media to build a profile of a user's behaviour nor are they used by Casale Media for the purposes of behavioural tracking or behavioural targeting. 
  2. They are used to facilitate retargeting at a campaign level. Retargeting is the process of serving an ad from a particular advertiser to a user, based on the fact that the user has previously visited the advertiser's website. Retargeting occurs within the confines of a user-to-advertiser relationship, and is not available for general targeting on the network. Retargeting is not available for sensitive health-related topics. 

**Third Party Data  
** Casale Media may obtain data from third party companies for the purpose of informing ad selection. This data is supplied in aggregate form and does not include any personally identifiable information (PII). 

**Opt-Out  
** Casale Media is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI), a cooperative of online marketing and analytics companies committed to building consumer awareness and establishing responsible business and data management practices and standards. To learn more or to opt out of targeted advertising from Casale Media and other NAI member networks, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

 **Collection and Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information  
** All information shared with both advertisers and publishers within the Casale Media online advertising network (MediaNet) is done so in an aggregate fashion. This allows us to provide clients of the advertising network with broad percentages regarding the users who are receiving advertisements through the network. This data is not linked to any form of personally identifiable information.

 **Data Retention  
** The unique user identification number, associated with when and how many times an individual has seen an advertisement, is deleted after 90 days of user inactivity. These unique IDs are not tied to any personally identifiable information. Aggregated statistical information, such as the popularity of an advertiser campaign, will be retained as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Log files are created to analyze trends, keep track of user movement in the aggregate and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. Log file data may be retained for up to a maximum period of fifteen months.

 **Collection and Use of Personally Identifiable Information by Advertisers  
** Advertisers who are clients of Casale Media may collect personally identifiable information on their own websites. These details provided directly by the individual Internet user in the form of online order forms, contests, or otherwise through the advertiser's website, are not visible to Casale Media. This personally identifiable information collected by the advertiser is subject to the privacy policy of the individual advertiser involved. 

**Online Behavioral Advertising  
** Casale Media adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance's Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising, <http://www.aboutads.info/>.

The Casale Media Online Advertising Network prides itself on providing an atmosphere that is non-disruptive to Internet users. Our proprietary targeting methodologies enable advertisers to effectively target their campaigns to the audience(s) they are looking to reach without engaging in profiling practices. 

**Web site (http://www.casalemedia.com/)**  
The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices of the Casale Media website, located at <http://www.casalemedia.com/>. 

Casale Media believes in all Internet users' rights to privacy. Casale Media does not engage in any form of distribution or sale of Personally Identifiable Information to third parties for their own promotional use, including but not limited to, names, email/postal addresses, and phone numbers. 

**Cookies  
** Casale Media uses session and persistent cookies, as well as web beacons on our website. These are needed for site navigation and to perform aggregate analysis of what is viewed on our site. 

**Collection and Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information  
** Like most standard website servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. Log file data may be retained for up to a maximum period of fifteen months.

 **Collection and Use of Personally Identifiable Information  
** Registering to become a member of the Casale Media online advertising network, either as an advertiser or a publisher, requires the submission of Personally Identifiable information to our company. This can include your full name, mailing and/or billing address, email address, company name, and website URL. We use this information to service your accounts and respond to inquiries. Communications to our business users are related to the Advertising Network. We hold all such information submitted in strict confidence. 

**Disclosure of your information  
** We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. 

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as submitting email communications to you on our behalf. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request
  * if we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so

 **Access to your information**  
If your personal information changes you may update or correct it by contacting us through our online form. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

 **Retention of data collected through our website  
** We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us through our online form. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

 **Security  
** We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. 

Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, please contact us using our online form.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

 **Changes to This Privacy Policy  
** Casale Media may find it necessary to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any changes will be posted at this site. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective.

 **Other information**   
Our site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Casale Media. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit.

With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us using our online form.

Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us using our online form.

 **Contact Us  
** To inquire about privacy concerns, please contact Casale Media by mail, as detailed below, or using our online form.

Casale Media Inc.  
74 Wingold Avenue  
Toronto, Ontario M6B1P5 Canada
